<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
	<id>com.shatteredpixel.shatteredpixeldungeon</id>
	<name>Shattered Pixel Dungeon</name>
	<summary>Roguelike RPG, with pixel art graphics and lots of variety and replayability</summary>
	<metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-3.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
	<!-- Description taken from https://shatteredpixel.com -->
	<description>
		<p>Shattered Pixel Dungeon is a Roguelike RPG, with pixel art graphics and lots of variety and replayability. Every game is unique, with four different playable characters, randomized levels and enemies, and over 150 items to collect and use. The game is simple to get into, but has lots of depth. Strategy is required if you want to win!</p>
		<p>This game is based on the freely available source code of Pixel Dungeon. It began as a project to improve on the original game's quirks, but has since evolved into a separate game, with many unique features.</p>
		<p>Shattered Pixel Dungeon includes:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>High replayability: Randomly generated levels, enemies, and items. No two games are the same!</li>
			<li>4 hero classes: Warrior, Mage, Rogue, and Huntress. Each hero has a unique playstyle.</li>
			<li>8 subclasses: Successful heroes can refine their skills to become more powerful.</li>
			<li>5 distinct dungeon regions: each with their own enemies, traps, and quests.</li>
			<li>Over 150 different items: including powerful wands, rings, weapons, and armor.</li>
			<li>50+ different enemies, 30 different traps, and 5 bosses to test your skills.</li>
			<li>Unique artifacts, which grow in power as you use them.</li>
			<li>Updates, with new content roughly once a month.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>Shattered Pixel Dungeon is a 100% free game. There are no advertisements, microtransactions, or paywalls. An optional donation to support the game unlocks a couple of fun extras, but these are entirely cosmetic and do not affect gameplay.</p>
		<p>Find an issue with the game? Have a suggestion? Then contact me! This game is a solo project, so the feedback of players is invaluable in improving the game. You can contact me at Evan@ShatteredPixel.com (My ability to respond to emails in languages other than English is limited.)</p>
		<p>Shattered Pixel Dungeon is available in multiple languages thanks to support from the community. The translation project is hosted here: https://www.transifex.com/shattered-pixel/shattered-pixel-dungeon</p>
		<p>Shattered Pixel Dungeon is open source software under the GPLv3 Licence. You can find the current source code here: https://github.com/00-Evan/shattered-pixel-dungeon</p>
	</description>
	<developer_name>Evan Debenham</developer_name>
	<url type="homepage">https://shatteredpixel.com/</url>
	<url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/00-Evan/shattered-pixel-dungeon</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/00-Evan/shattered-pixel-dungeon/issues</url>
	<url type="translate">https://www.transifex.com/shattered-pixel/shattered-pixel-dungeon/</url>
	<url type="donation">https://www.patreon.com/ShatteredPixel</url>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.shatteredpixel.shatteredpixeldungeon/master/screenshot1.png</image>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.shatteredpixel.shatteredpixeldungeon/master/screenshot2.png</image>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.shatteredpixel.shatteredpixeldungeon/master/screenshot3.png</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<releases>
		<release version="2.1.2" date="2023-06-16">
			<description>
				<p>v2.1.0 includes a bunch of Duelist balance changes, three new weapons, two new exotic enemies, and a bunch of big and small tweaks and bugfixes.</p>
			</description>
			<url>https://shatteredpixel.com/blog/shattered-pixel-dungeon-v210.html</url>
		</release>
		<release version="2.1.1" date="2023-06-13">
			<description>
				<p>v2.1.0 includes a bunch of Duelist balance changes, three new weapons, two new exotic enemies, and a bunch of big and small tweaks and bugfixes.</p>
			</description>
			<url>https://shatteredpixel.com/blog/shattered-pixel-dungeon-v210.html</url>
		</release>
		<release version="2.1.0" date="2023-06-02">
			<description>
				<p>v2.1.0 includes a bunch of Duelist balance changes, three new weapons, two new exotic enemies, and a bunch of big and small tweaks and bugfixes.</p>
			</description>
			<url>https://shatteredpixel.com/blog/shattered-pixel-dungeon-v210.html</url>
		</release>
		<release version="2.0.0" date="2023-03-13">
			<description>
				<p>v2.0.0 includes Shattered's first ever new playable character! The Duelist is a melee weapons specialist who has a unique ability for every weapon in the game. Just like the other heroes, she has 2 subclasses, 3 armor abilities, and 26 talents!</p>
			</description>
			<url>https://shatteredpixel.com/blog/shattered-pixel-dungeon-v200.html</url>
		</release>
		<release version="1.4.3" date="2022-11-19">
			<description>
				<p>v1.4.0 is focused on new in-game lore and loads of other miscellaneous improvements. There are 30 pages of story text to find, a new ring, various reworks, a new tutorial, and over a hundred smaller tweaks and fixes!</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.4.0" date="2022-09-04">
			<description>
				<p>v1.4.0 is focused on new in-game lore and loads of other miscellaneous improvements. There are 30 pages of story text to find, a new ring, various reworks, a new tutorial, and over a hundred smaller tweaks and fixes!</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.3.2" date="2022-07-27">
			<description>
				<p>v1.3.0 includes a variety of additions and improvements, including a new scoring system, custom seeds and daily runs, and a harder alternate ending! There are also some new and changed badges, various UI and control improvements, and a bunch of balance tweaks.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.3.0" date="2022-07-06">
			<description>
				<p>v1.3.0 includes a variety of additions and improvements, including a new scoring system, custom seeds and daily runs, and a harder alternate ending! There are also some new and changed badges, various UI and control improvements, and a bunch of balance tweaks.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.2.3" date="2022-04-14">
			<description>
				<p>v1.2 is the first version of Shattered built for computers! It has a bunch of improvements for users on larger screens and who play with controllers or mouse and keyboard! There are also several content changes, including new special rooms, a rework to the Master Thieves' Armband, and various improvements to spell items.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.2.0+1" date="2022-03-26">
			<description>
				<p>Fix: With v1.2.0 a new save path was introduced, which is moving content to a new location. This new path wasn't persisted.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.2.0" date="2022-03-23">
			<description>
				<p>v1.2 is the first version of Shattered built for computers! It has a bunch of improvements for users on larger screens and who play with controllers or mouse and keyboard! There are also several content changes, including new special rooms, a rework to the Master Thieves' Armband, and various improvements to spell items.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.1.1" date="2022-01-04">
			<description>
				<p>v1.1.0 contains various improvements to the alchemy system and the items it produces, and a music track for each region of the game! There are a few new spells, and several buffs and reworks to exotic potions and scrolls in particular, and various other smaller changes.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.0.3" date="2021-09-01">
			<description>
				<p>v1.0.0 is here! It contains a variety of content additions and refinements. There is new music, support for new platforms, new alchemy recipes, and a few other odds and ends.</p>
				<p>I've also made a bunch of balance changes to hero abilities and various items.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="1.0.0" date="2021-08-17">
			<description>
				<p>v1.0.0 is here! It contains a variety of content additions and refinements. There is new music, support for new platforms, new alchemy recipes, and a few other odds and ends.</p>
				<p>I've also made a bunch of balance changes to hero abilities and various items.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.3" date="2021-06-07">
			<description>
				<p>v0.9.3 redesigns hero armor abilities and adds a fourth tier to the talent system! There are 13 abilities and 40 new talents in total.</p>
				<p>There's also a new challenge, balance changes, bugfixes and various smaller tweaks.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.2b" date="2021-02-26">
			<description>
				<p>v0.9.2 adds the third tier of the talent system, which interacts with hero subclasses and is the most significant tier yet! There are also a bunch of balance changes to the various classes/subclasses, and enemies in the late prison and deeper.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.2" date="2021-01-26">
			<description>
				<p>v0.9.2 adds the third tier of the talent system, which interacts with hero subclasses and is the most significant tier yet! There are also a bunch of balance changes to the various classes/subclasses, and enemies in the late prison and deeper.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.1" date="2020-12-11">
			<description>
				<p>v0.9.1 introduces the second tier of the talent system and makes some major improvements to the first tier! There is also a major expansion to the level generation algorithm and a bunch of smaller additions and improvements.</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.0" date="2020-10-05">
			<description>
				<p>v0.9.0 is the first in a series of updates that will introduce and build upon a new gameplay system! As your hero levels up you can now spend talent points to give them new or improved abilities!</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.8.2" date="2020-08-06">
			<description>
				<p>v0.8.2 includes major interface improvements and additions, a new equipment slot for rings/artifacts, and a bunch of smaller improvements and balance tweaks!</p>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.8.1" date="2020-06-28">
	        	<description>
              			<p> This update totally overhauls enemies and bosses in the middle and late stages of the game! v0.8.1 includes some major audiovisual upgrades in the form of new sounds effects and a redesigned hero select featuring fully detailed splash art! There are also lots of design and balance tweaks to bosses, items, and general gameplay.</p>
           		</description>
        	</release>
		<release version="0.8.0b" date="2019-12-01" />
	</releases>
	<categories>
		<category>Game</category>
		<category>StrategyGame</category>
	</categories>
	<recommends>
		<control>keyboard</control>
	</recommends>
	<supports>
		<control>pointing</control>
		<control>gamepad</control>
	</supports>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1">
		<content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">moderate</content_attribute>
		<content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">mild</content_attribute>
	</content_rating>
</component>
